Guide to the American Veterans Committee records, 1942-2002 MS2144
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Subjects, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 1
  - Women veterans, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 1, Subseries 3
    - WIMSA - rationale and statement of expenses, 1988-1991 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - WIMSA Report re: board member compensation, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - WIMSA site, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - WIMSA - support organizations, 1985-1987 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - WIMSA testimony [1/2], 1985-1986 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - WIMSA testimony [2/2], 1985-1986 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - WIMSA - Vaught, Wilma, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - "The Woman Veteran" - AVC testimony, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Women in the military, 1980 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Women's Army Corps, 1978-1979 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Women's Bureau, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Women's Bureau application and study, 1984-1985 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Women's Bureau Project - analysis of first survey, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Women's Bureau Project - contract, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Women's Bureau Project - data, 1983-1984 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Women's Bureau Project drafts [1/2], undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Women's Bureau Project drafts [2/2], undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Women's Bureau Project - final report, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Women's Bureau Project - financial, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Women's Bureau Project - financial [1/2], 1985-1986 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Women's Bureau Project - financial [2/2], 1985-1986 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Women's Bureau Project - interview questions, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Women's Bureau Project - legal correspondence, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Women's Bureau Project proposal, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Women's Bureau Project questionnaires [1/5], 1984-1985 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Women's Bureau project questionnaires [2/5], 1984-1985 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Women's Bureau project questionnaires [3/5], 1984-1985 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Women's Bureau project questionnaires [4/5], 1984-1985 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Women's Bureau project questionnaires [5/5], 1984-1985 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Women's Bureau project questionnaire letters, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Women's Bureau project - report comments, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Women's Bureau project - States' responses to questionnaires, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Women's Bureau project - tables and notes, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Women's Bureau proposals, 1980-1983 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Women's Bureau proposal materials [1/2], 1988 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Women's Bureau proposal materials [2/2], 1988 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Women's Bureau report, 11/1984 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Women's Bureau report, 12/1984 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Women's Bureau report, 01/1985 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Women's Bureau report, 02/1985 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Women's Bureau report, 03/1985 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Women's Bureau report, 04/1985 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Women's Bureau report, 05/1985 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Women's Bureau report, 06/1985 --07/1985 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Women's Bureau report, 08/1985 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Women's Bureau report, 11/1985 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Women's Bureau report, 12/1985 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Women's Bureau report, 1988 (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Women's Bureau report - drafts and notes, undated (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Women's Bureau tables, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Women marines, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Women in combat, 1987-1991 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Women's employment study data [1/2], 1985 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Women's employment study data [2/2], 1985 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Women in the military, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Women in the military - publications, 1977-1982 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Women in Nontraditional Careers conference, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Women's organizations, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "Women Veterans" book, 1984-1985 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Women Veterans" book, 1987-1989 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - "Women Veterans: America's Forgotten Heroines" - reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - "Women Veterans" book - bibliography, undated (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Women veterans - Civil Service Commission statistics, 1977-1979 (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Women veterans - correspondence [1/2], 1977-1981 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Women veterans - correspondence [2/2], 1977-1981 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Women veterans - Defense statistics, 1978-1979 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Women veterans demonstration proposal - Dennis Rhoades, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Women Veterans: A Demonstration Project", 1980 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Women veterans - Dept. of Defense correspondence, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - "Women Veterans" draft by June Willenz [1/2], 1983 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - "Women Veterans" draft by June Willenz [2/2], 1983 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "Women Veterans - A Forgotten Population" Advisory Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Women veterans - foundation correspondence, 1973-1982 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Women veterans - Government agency statistics, 1977-1979 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Women veterans' health care, 1984-1993 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Women Veterans Health Equity Act of 1991, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Women veterans - labor statistics, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Women veterans legislation, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Women Veterans Memorial proposal, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Women veterans - miscellaneous, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Women veterans - Pentagon correspondence, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Women veterans - private research statistics, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Women veterans project - support, 1980-1981 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Women veterans - proposals [1/2], undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Women veterans - proposals [2/2], undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Women veterans - proposal appendices, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Women veterans - proposal drafts, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Women veterans - Proposal Phase I, undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Women veterans - publicity, 1979-1981 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Women veterans - questionnaires, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Women veterans - short proposal, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Women veterans - statistics, 1977-1978 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Women veterans - Veterans Administration statistics, 1977-1979 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - "Women Veterans from the Vietnam War: Through the Eighties", 1985 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Women in and after War, 1986 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Discharge review, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 1, Subseries 4
    - AAMPVA, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Air Force Discharge Review Board, 1974-1982 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Army Discharge Review Board, 1974-1976 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Army drug program, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Attorneys, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - AVC v. Schlesinger; Bonner v. Laird, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Cases, Board of Veteran Appeals, 1976-1984 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Checklist for veterans seeking change of discharge, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Clemency Board, 1974-1976 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - "Clemency Discharge: A Help or a Hoax?", undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Clemency program, 1974-1975 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - Department of Defense on discharge review, 1969-1978 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - discharge review cases, 1951-1956 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - discharge review cases, 1974-1975 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - discharge review cases [1/2], 1976-1979 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - discharge review cases [2/2], 1976-1979 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - discharge review cases, 1980-1990 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - discharge review cases A-F, 1966-1988 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - discharge review cases G-N, 1974-1986 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - discharge review cases O-Z, 1977-1984 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - "Facts on Other-than-Honorable Discharges", 1976-1979 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence re: SDRP, 1977 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - lawyers, 1973-1976 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re: "legal hold", 1975 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with VA re: less-than-honorably discharged veterans, 1971-1977 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Courts-martial, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - The Danforth Foundation, 1973-1975 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Discharge data, 1977-1981 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Discharge issues, 1971-1980 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Discharge reform bill, 1974-1977 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Discharge review [1/2], 1972-1981 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Discharge review [2/2], 1972-1981 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Discharge review - attorneys, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Discharge Review Board, 1980-1981 (Box 48, Folder 2, Box R1, Folder 1)
      General note
      Please note: This folder contains materials that are restricted. Please see Staff for assistance.
    - Discharge review briefs, 1975-1976 (Box 48, Folder 3, Box R1, Folder 2)
    - Discharge review cases - A-D, 1968-1976 (Box 48, Folder 4, Box R1, Folder 3)
    - Discharge review cases - D, 1973-1979 (Box R1, Folder 4, Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Discharge review cases - E-L, 1968-1976 (Box R1, Folder 5, Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Discharge review cases - M-R, 1968-1976 (Box R2, Folder 1, Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Discharge review cases - S-Z, 1968-1976 (Box R2, Folder 2, Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Discharge review cases before the VA, 1967-1975 (Box 48, Folder 9, Box R2, Folder 3)
    - Discharge review category listings and statistics, 1967-1986 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Discharge review deadline, 1979-1980 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Discharge review deadline extension, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Discharge review form letters, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Discharge review government correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Discharge review handbook [1/2], 1973-1976 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Discharge review handbook [2/2], 1973-1976 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Discharge review materials, 1969-1981 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Discharge review - other organizations, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Discharge review procedures, 1971-1978 (Box 50, Folder 10, Box R2, Folder 4)
    - Discharge review projects, 1976-1978 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Discharge review proposals [1/2], 1965-1978 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Discharge review proposals [2/2], 1965-1978 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Discharge review regulations, 1977-1983 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Discharge review uniform published rules and regulations, 1978 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Discharge review witnesses, 1974 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Discharge statistics, 1969-1972 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Discharge upgrading proposal correspondence, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Discharge upgrading seminar, 1976 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Expeditious Discharge Program, 1975 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Extension of statue of limitations for discharge review, 1979-1981 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Facts on other- than- honorable discharges, 1973 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Georgetown discharge lawsuit, 1975-1976 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Georgetown University discharge cases, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Guide to the Special Discharge Review Program, 1977 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Guidelines for Caseworkers in Discharge Review and Correction of Military and Naval Records, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Heiler v. Williams, 1976-1977 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - JAG corrections to discharge handbook, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Judicial review of VA decisions, 1977-1988 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Judicial review, 1977-1979 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Judicial review, 1977-1985 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Law schools, 1967-1976 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Lawyer recruitment, 1973-1974 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Lawyers' luncheon, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - LEAA, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Legal aid, 1960-1970 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Legal aid funding, 1973-1974 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Legal Aid program statement, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Legal aid project: correspondence with Office of Economic Opportunity, 1967-1969 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Legal aid project proposals, 1970-1973 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Legal aid proposals [1/2], 1974 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Legal aid proposals [2/2], 1974 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Less- than- honorable discharges, 1958-1959 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Less- than- honorable discharges, 1974-1981 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Less- than- honorable discharges - amnesty, 1977 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Less- than- Honorable Discharges: A Study, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - McGovern bill on discharge, 1973-1974 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - "Military Discharge Policies and their Impacts", undated (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Military regulations, 1966-1973 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Navy Discharge Review Board, 1974-1975 (Box R3, Folder 1, Box 54, Folder 6)
    - "The Need for Change of the Military Discharge System", undated (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - New York City legal aid, 1974-1976 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Notes and Comments on Department of Defense Directive 1332.14, 1965 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Outline of AVC's Legal Aid Program for Veterans, undated (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Peabody, Endicott - lunch, 1973 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - President Carter's Special Discharge Review Program [1/3], 1977 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - President Carter's Special Discharge Review Program [2/3], 1977 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - President Carter's Special Discharge Review Program [3/3], 1977 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - President Carter's Special Discharge Review Program - correspondence and drafts, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - President Ford's Clemency Program, 1973-1974 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - President Ford's Clemency Program, 1975-1976 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - President Ford's Clemency Program, hearings, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Prisoner correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 55, Folder 5, Box R3, Folder 2)
    - Procedures for discharge review, 1973-1977 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Red Cross discharge review handbook, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Report of AVC discharge review representative, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Robert R. Nathan Associates, 1974-1980 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Reports on Other- than- Honorable Discharges, undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Search for legal aid lawyers, 1973-1978 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Special Discharge Review Program, 1974-1976 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Special Discharge Review Program, 1977-1978 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Special Discharge Review Program counselling center proposal, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - SPN correspondence, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - SPN correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 56, Folder 3, Box R3)
    - SPN policy, 1970-1975 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Statistics on race and discharge, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - VA cases, 1981-1982 (Box 56, Folder 6, Box R3, Folder 4)
    - VA cases, 1984-1985 (Box 56, Folder 7, Box R3, Folder 5)
    - VA cases, 1986-1990 (Box R3, Folder 6, Box 56, Folder 8)
    - VA discharge lists, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - VA discharge policy, 1975-1976 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - VA regulations, 1968-1972 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Veteran correspondence re: SDRP, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - "Vets in Prison" proposal, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Washington, D.C., area legal aid, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Washington, D.C. discharge cases, 1974 (Box R3, Folder 7, Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Washington University Military Law Project, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - White House correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Willenz issue papers, 1976-1977 (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Wynn, Thomas, 1992-1994 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Veterans' education and employment, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 1, Subseries 5
    - Campaign for Employee Rights, 1994-1995 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Carter budget, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Coalition for a Fair Minimum Wage, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Department of Labor, 1975-1978 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re: educational benefits, 1974-1975 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Office of Education, 1972 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1975-1977 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Education of veterans, 1974-1977 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Education of Vietnam veterans, 1972-1977 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Employment, 1945-1953 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Employment Service, 1986 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Employment of veterans, 1974-1986 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Employment of Vietnam veterans, 1977 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Full employment, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - GI Bill, 1965-1968 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - GI Bill [1/2], 1969 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - GI Bill [2/2], 1969 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - GI Bill [1/2], 1974 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - GI Bill [2/2], 1974 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - GI Bill, 1975 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - GI Bill, 1976 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - GI Bill, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - GI Bill [1/2], 1980-1981 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - GI Bill [2/2], 1980-1981 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - GI Bill, 1982-1984 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - GI Bill, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Humphrey - Hawkins Bill and full employment, 1978 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Jepson Bill on ex- military wives, 1982 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Jobs program for veterans, 1977 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Labor law reform, 1978 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - "Other- than- Honorable Discharges: Their Impacts Upon Employment Opportunities", undated (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Report on the Emergency Veterans' Job Training Program, undated (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Targeted Jobs Tax Credit, 1992-1993 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 1993, undated (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - VA and education, 1977-1981 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - VA and employment, 1985 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Veteran medics, 1973 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Veterans in Business Opportunity Conference, 1990 (Box 253, Folder 11)
    - Veterans' employment and readjustment problems, 1970 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Veterans Employment Service, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Veterans' preference [1/2], 1977-1979 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Veterans' preference [2/2], 1977-1979 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Veterans' preference, 1983-1984 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Veterans' preference - civil rights, 1977-1978 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Veterans' preference testimony, 1978-1984 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - "Workforce 2000 and America's Veterans", 1988 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Veterans' health, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 1, Subseries 6
    - Agent Orange, 1978-1980 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Agent Orange [1/2], 1981-1987 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Agent Orange [2/2], 1981-1987 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Agent Orange, 1988-1994 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Aging veterans, 1980-1981 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Catastophic health insurance, 1986-1987 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Coordinating Federal Health Care conference, 1993 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Coorespondence - Gulf War Syndrome, 1994-1997 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Federal Employees Group Life Insurance, 1985 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Geriatric and Gerontology Health Services Act, 1978 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Gulf War Syndrome, 1993-1998 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Health care reform, 1993 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Health care reform, 1998-2000 (Box 253, Folder 12)
    - Health care and Social Security, 1978-1981 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Health issues, 1977-1993 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - National health insurance, 1974-1980 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - National Pharmacies, 1979 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Paramedical training, 1971-1972 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Persian Gulf diseases, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Radiation survivors, 1985-1992 (Box 63, Folder 8)
    - Ranch Hand study (Agent Orange), 1999-2000 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - VA health care, 1977-1983 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - VA health care, 1996-2002 (Box 253, Folder 13)
    - VA medical schools, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Veterans' benefits, 1970-1981 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Veteran Senior Citizen Health Care Act, 1979 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - National service, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 1, Subseries 7
    - Coalition for National Service, 1988 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Coalition in Support of Voluntary National Youth Service, 1979 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - correspondence, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - honorary co-chairs, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - invitations, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - lists, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - panelists, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - program, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - proposal and pamphlet, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - questionnaires, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - speakers, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - steering committee, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Dialogue on National Service conference - White House correspondence, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Gallup poll on national service, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - National service, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - National service, 1976-1979 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - National service [1/3], 1979-1980 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - National service [2/3], 1979-1980 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - National service [3/3], 1979-1980 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - National service, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - National service, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - National service, 1991-1993 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - National service - alternative service, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - National service and the American Veterans Committee, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - National service - Johns Hopkins, 1988 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - National service legislation, undated (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - National service - Soviet Union, 1988-1989 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - National service - Terrence Cullinan, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - National service - testimony, 1980-1982 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - National Youth Service Program, 1980 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Youth Service America, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Other veterans' groups, 1946-2000; MS2144 Series 1, Subseries 8
    - 11th Federal Assembly of the Reichsbund - Berlin, 1987 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Association of French War Veterans, 1985 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Baltimore Veterans' Council, 1973 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Blinded Veterans Association, 1975-1977 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Canadian veterans, 1984 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Center for Minority Veterans, 1994 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Center for Veterans Issues (black, minority, and women veterans), 1988-1989 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Coalition of veterans' groups, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Disabled American Veterans, 1993-1996 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Gold Star Wives, 1986-1997 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Jewish War Veterans of the United States of America, 1984-1985 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - National Association of Black Veterans, 1974 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - National Association of Collegiate Veterans, 1973-1982 (Box 69, Folder 1)